<chapter id="troubleshooting">
    <title>Troubleshooting</title>
    <para>TubePress is designed to work on any server that runs PHP5, and it's
        designed to be experienced by any web browser in any operating system.
        Given the
        vast number of possible permutations of these elements, it's no
        surprise that a small percentage of TubePress installations just won't
        quite work the way
        they should. The good news is that 90% of installation
        problems can be diagnosed and resolved by following the simple
        guidelines listed in this section.</para>
    <section id="debugging">
        <title>Debugging</title>
        <para>
            Putting TubePress into debug mode will dump a large amount of
            information to the screen. To use it, you just need to add
            <code>tubepress_debug=true</code>
            to the URL string (in your browser's address bar). For instance, if
            the TubePress page you're trying to debug
            has an address of
            <code>http://ehough.com/?page_id=19</code>
            then you should add
            <code>tubepress_debug=true</code>
            to the URL to enable
            debugging:
            <code>http://ehough.com/?page_id=19&amp;tubepress_debug=true</code>
            .
        </para>
        <para>
            Most of the debug output is self-explanatory. If the output is cut off
            unexpectedly, it's likely that TubePress encountered a fatal error
            while building a gallery. Check your PHP error logs for more
            information.
            </para>
    </section>
    <section id="youtube-connection-test">
        <title>YouTube Connection Test</title>
        <para>
            Some web servers place restrictions on what PHP functions are
            allowed to execute. TubePress needs the ability
            to open network connections to remote servers. One way to verify that TubePress
            has this ability is to run
            the YouTube connection test. You can find a link to the test in the
            <link linkend="debugging">debug output</link>
            . The test
            will attempt to retrieve the HTML content of YouTube's homepage, and then it will
            execute a sample video query
            against YouTube's API. The result of the latter will be printed to the screen as
            plain XML.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section id="head-elements-check">
        <title>Check for required CSS and JS includes</title>
        <para>
            Any page that uses TubePress needs to have
            <code>tubepress.css</code>
            and
            <code>tubepress.js</code>
            loaded in the HTML head of the document.
            If these files are missing, your galleries will show up unstyled (ugly!) and
            non-functional; thumbnails won't respond to clicking on them. You
            can view
            your HTML source or use
            <ulink url="http://getfirebug.com">FireBug</ulink>
            to verify if these files are being loaded correctly.
        </para>
        <para>
            In WordPress, these files are automatically loaded via your theme's
            <code>wp_head()</code>
            function invocation. However, some custom themes
            will (accidentally
            or intentionally) omit this call. Switching back to the "classic"
            WordPress theme will verify if your custom theme is the culprit.
            <ulink
                url="http://josephscott.org/archives/2009/04/wordpress-theme-authors-dont-forget-the-wp_head-function/">Here</ulink>
            is some further information
            on including the
            <code>wp_head()</code>
            function in your theme.
        </para>
        <para>
            In TubePress Pro, you just need to make sure that you include the
            <code><?php print tubepressHeadElements(true); ?>
            </code>
            statement somewhere in
            the head of your HTML document. See the
            <link linkend="plain-php">TubePress Pro usage instructions</link>
            for more information.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section id="discussion-forum">
        <title>Discussion Forum</title>
        <para>
            Still can't solve your issue? Try searching or posting in the
            <ulink url="http://groups.google.com/group/tubepress-users">
                TubePress discussion forum</ulink>
            , hosted by Google Groups. It is
            <emphasis>strongly</emphasis>
            recommended that you send along a link
            to your gallery if you're experiencing difficulty.
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>The forum is open to the public for reading, but you'll need a
                Google Account to post</para>
        </note>
    </section>
    <section id="open-an-issue">
        <title>Open an Issue</title>
        <para>
            If you can't find a solution to your problem in the
            <link linkend="discussion-forum">discussion forum</link>
            , someone may have already submitted a trouble
            ticket. The current list of issues can be found at
            <ulink url="http://code.google.com/p/tubepress/issues/list">http://code.google.com/p/tubepress/issues/list
            </ulink>
            . Please feel
            free to submit a trouble ticket or feature request.
        </para>
        <note>
            <para>The issues list is open to the public for reading, but you'll
                need a Google Account to post a new issue or comment on an
                existing issue</para>
        </note>
    </section>
</chapter>